Class of 1886 Records, 1873-1950s, 1970s-1990s
Smith College Archives
Class of 1886 Records
1873-1950s, 1970s-1990s
Smith College. Class of 1886.
RG 80 UUID:d9c2c5c6-764c-4395-a52a-6f4adaa9a2ce
10 boxes (4 linear ft. and 2 linear inches)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
This collection contains black and white photographs, letters, class letters, correspondence, newspaper, magazine, and journal articles, student notes, scrapbooks, and information from the commencement and reunions of the Class of 1886.
Historical Note
The Class of 1886 was the eighth graduating class of Smith College.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Class of 1886 Records contain materials describing the history of the Class of 1886. Types of materials include black and white photographs, letters, class letters, correspondence, newspaper, magazine, and journal articles, student notes, scrapbooks, and information from the commencement and reunions of the Class of 1886.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
History of the Collection
The Class of 1886 Records were created by the students and donated to the College Archives.
- Class of 1886: Baccalaureate Service 1886 (Box 1425, Folder 1)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters 1904, 1906, 1911, 1915-19, 1921, 1925, 1927-28, 1930-33, 1936, 1942 (Box 1425, Folder 2)
- Class of 1886: Commencement 1886 (Box 1425, Folder 3)
- Class of 1886: Commencement Music 1886 (Box 1425, Folder 4)
- Class of 1886: Composite Photography 1886 (Box 1425, Folder 5)
- Class of 1886: Freshman Farewell to 1883 1883 (Box 1425, Folder 6)
- Class of 1886: Germans 1884, 1886 (Box 1425, Folder 7)
- Class of 1886: Groups 1883, 1886, other n.d. (Box 1425, Folder 8)
- Class of 1886: History 1911, 1932 (Box 1425, Folder 9)
- Class of 1886: Ivy Day 1886 (Box 1425, Folder 10)
- Class of 1886: Junior Prom 1885 (Box 1425, Folder 11)
- Class of 1886: Junior Reception 1885 (Box 1425, Folder 12)
- Class of 1886: Records 1882-1931 (Box 1425, Folder 13)
- Class of 1886: Reunions 1921, other n.d. (Box 1425, Folder 14)
- Class of 1886: Reunions (1916- Seelye Victrola Record) 1916-20, 1924 (Box 1425, Folder 15)
- Class of 1886: Reunions (1916- Seelye Victrola Record, Correspondence) 1918-19 (Box 1425, Folder 16)
- Class of 1886: Reunions (1925) 1925 (Box 1425, Folder 17)
- Class of 1886: Reunions (1931) 1931 (Box 1425, Folder 18)
- Class of 1886: Reunions (1933) 1933 (Box 1425, Folder 19)
- Class of 1886: Reunions (1936) 1936 (Box 1425, Folder 20)
- Class of 1886: Reunions (1941) 1941 (Box 1425, Folder 21)
- Class of 1886: Reunions (1946) 1946 (Box 1425, Folder 22)
- Class of 1886: Senior Dramatics 1886 (Box 1425, Folder 23)
- Class of 1886: Songs N.d. (Box 1425, Folder 24)
- Class of 1886: Sophomore Reception 1882 (Box 1425, Folder 25)
- Class of 1886: Sophomore-Senior Reception for 1884 1884 (Box 1425, Folder 26)
- Class of 1886: Class Supper 1886, 1916 (Box 1425, Folder 27)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1887) 1887 (Box 1426, Folder 1)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1888) 1888 (Box 1426, Folder 2)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1892) 1892 (Box 1426, Folder 3)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1893) 1893 (Box 1426, Folder 4)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1894) 1894 (Box 1426, Folder 5)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1895) 1895 (Box 1426, Folder 6)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1896) 1896 (Box 1426, Folder 7)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1897) 1897 (Box 1426, Folder 8)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1898) 1898 (Box 1426, Folder 9)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1900) 1900 (Box 1426, Folder 10)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1901) 1901 (Box 1426, Folder 11)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1931-32) 1931-32 (Box 1426, Folder 12)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1932-33) 1932-33 (Box 1426, Folder 13)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1933-34) 1933-34 (Box 1426, Folder 14)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1934-35) 1934-35 (Box 1426, Folder 15)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1935-36) 1935-36 (Box 1426, Folder 16)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1936-37) 1936-37 (Box 1426, Folder 17)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1937-38) 1937-38 (Box 1426, Folder 18)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1938-39) 1938-39 (Box 1426, Folder 19)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1939-40) 1939-40 (Box 1426, Folder 20)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1940-41) 1940-41 (Box 1426, Folder 21)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1941-42) 1941-42 (Box 1426, Folder 22)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1942-43) 1942-43 (Box 1426, Folder 23)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1943-44) 1943-44 (Box 1426, Folder 24)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1944-45) 1944-45 (Box 1426, Folder 25)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1945-46) 1945-46 (Box 1426, Folder 26)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1946-47) 1946-47 (Box 1426, Folder 27)
- Class of 1886: Class Letters (1947-48) 1947-48 (Box 1426, Folder 28)
- Class of 1886: Aldrich, May Moore N.d. (Box 1427, Folder 1)
- Class of 1886: Allen, Mary Adele 1908, 1915, 1917, 1928, 1931, 1939, other n.d. (Box 1427, Folder 2)
- Class of 1886: Allen, Mary Adele (Photographs, etc) 1882, 1884, 1886, 1909, 1925, 1928, 1937, other n.d. (Box 1427, Folder 3)
- Class of 1886: Anderson, Jessie McMillan ("Three Freshmen: Ruth, Fran, and Nathalie") 1895 (Box 1427, Folder 4)
- Class of 1886: Anderson, Jessie McMillan (Photographs, etc) 1885, 1891, 1943, other n.d. (Box 1427, Folder 5)
- Class of 1886: Atwater, Margaret Clarke (Photographs, etc) 1921, other n.d. (Box 1427, Folder 6)
- Class of 1886: Baker, Mary Chamberlain (Photographs) 1886, 1888 (Box 1427, Folder 7)
- Class of 1886: Bradbury, Alice Emerson (Photographs, etc) N.d. (Box 1427, Folder 8)
- Class of 1886: Bradbury, Marion (Photographs, etc) 1882-84, 1932 (Box 1427, Folder 9)
- Class of 1886: Bradley, Emma Louise 1932 (Box 1427, Folder 10)
- Class of 1886: Burleigh, Charlotte Russell (Box 1427, Folder 11)
- Class of 1886: Carter, Mary Abigail (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1427, Folder 12)
- Class of 1886: Clough, Mabelle Beatrice 1932 (Box 1427, Folder 13)
- Class of 1886: Conant, Jennie Frances 1900, 1903 (Box 1427, Folder 14)
- Class of 1886: Cook, Mabell Melissa 1931 (Box 1427, Folder 15)
- Class of 1886: Corns, Sarah Ann (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1427, Folder 16)
- Class of 1886: Cushman, Hattie Frances (Correspondence) 1911, 1936 (Box 1427, Folder 17)
- Class of 1886: Davis, Ellen Rich (Box 1427, Folder 18)
- Class of 1886: Dole, Sara L. N.d. (Box 1427, Folder 19)
- Class of 1886: Duncan, Margaretta (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1427, Folder 20)
- Class of 1886: Eastman, Elizabeth (Correspondence) 1885-87 (Box 1427, Folder 21)
- Class of 1886: Eastman, Elizabeth (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1427, Folder 22)
- Class of 1886: Eastman, Mary (Box 1427, Folder 23)
- Class of 1886: Edgerton, Lillian (Special, Music 1882-83) N.d. (Box 1427, Folder 24)
- Class of 1886: Ferry, Isabelle (Herrmann) N.d. (Box 1427, Folder 25)
- Class of 1886: Freeland, Elizabeth King (Correspondence) 1886 (Box 1427, Folder 26)
- Class of 1886: Freeland, Elizabeth King (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1427, Folder 27)
- Class of 1886: Fowler, Esther B. 1897, 1899, 1902, 1909-10, 1917, 1929, other n.d. (Box 1427, Folder 28)
- Class of 1886: Fuller, Jessie Ginevra (Photographs, etc) N.d. (Box 1427, Folder 29)
- Class of 1886: Gallaudet, Grace Worden N.d. (Box 1427, Folder 30)
- Class of 1886: Gallaudet, Grace Worden (Photographs) 1881-83 (Box 1427, Folder 31)
- Class of 1886: Gilman, Frances Chandler (Photographs) 1885 (Box 1427, Folder 32)
- Class of 1886: Gooding, Edith (Correspondence) 1886 (Box 1427, Folder 33)
- Class of 1886: Gooding, Edith (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1427, Folder 34)
- Class of 1886: Goodnow, Anna Marion (Photographs) 1888 (Box 1427, Folder 35)
- Class of 1886: Goodwin, Frances Cullis (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1427, Folder 36)
- Class of 1886: Gould, Grace Evelyn (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1427, Folder 37)
- Class of 1886: Harding, Harriet N.d. (Box 1427, Folder 38)
- Class of 1886: Hemenway, Sarah Gross (Photographs, etc) 1883, other n.d. (Box 1427, Folder 39)
- Class of 1886: Hill, (Harriet) Hattie Bell 1950 (Box 1427, Folder 40)
- Class of 1886: Howes, Abigail Christina (Correspondence) 1886-87, other n.d. (Box 1427, Folder 41)
- Class of 1886: Howes, Abigail Christina (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1427, Folder 42)
- Class of 1886: Hurlburt, Katherine Maria (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1427, Folder 43)
- Class of 1886: Kidder, Mabel Agnes (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1428, Folder 1)
- Class of 1886: Kyle, Helen Sherwood (Correspondence) 1884-87 (Box 1428, Folder 2)
- Class of 1886: Kyle, Helen Sherwood (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1428, Folder 3)
- Class of 1886: Lathrop, Clara Welles 1907 (Box 1428, Folder 4)
- Class of 1886: Merriam, Florence Augusta (Box 1428, Folder 5)
- Class of 1886: Peirce, Leona May 1901, other n.d. (Box 1428, Folder 6)
- Class of 1886: Perkins, Sarah Huntington (Correspondence) 1884-87 (Box 1428, Folder 7)
- Class of 1886: Perkins, Sarah Huntington (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1428, Folder 8)
- Class of 1886: Perry, Jeanette Barbour (Box 1428, Folder 9)
- Class of 1886: Ray, Bertha Cornwall (Photographs, etc) 1921, other n.d. (Box 1428, Folder 10)
- Class of 1886: Risley, Harriett Eliza (Photographs, etc) 1904, 1913, 1923, 1926-27, 1929, 1937, 1948, 1991-92, other n.d. (Box 1428, Folder 11)
- Class of 1886: Ruble, Zulema Alice (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1428, Folder 12)
- Class of 1886: Russell, Annie Maria (Photographs, etc) 1931, 1936, other n.d. (Box 1428, Folder 13)
- Class of 1886: Russell, Annie Maria (Writings) 1907-08, 1911-12, 1916, 1920, 1922-24, 1926-32, 1935-36 (Box 1428, Folder 14)
- Class of 1886: Russell, Annie Maria (Writings) 1901-02, 1920-21, 1930, 1936 (Box 1428, Folder 15)
- Class of 1886: Safford, Mary Bigelow (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1428, Folder 16)
- Class of 1886: Seelye, Henrietta Hurd (Photographs, etc) 1883, 1885, 1925, 1931-32, 1936 (Box 1428, Folder 17)
- Class of 1886: Slade, Abby Maria (Correspondence, etc) 1880, 1882-87, 1894 (Box 1428, Folder 18)
- Class of 1886: Smith, Florence (Photographs, etc) 1873, 1880, 1885-86 (Box 1428, Folder 19)
- Class of 1886: Stebbins, Mary Granger N.d. (Box 1428, Folder 20)
- Class of 1886: Topliff, Susan Caroline 1884, 1886 (Box 1428, Folder 21)
- Class of 1886: Tuckerman, Florence Sophia (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1428, Folder 22)
- Class of 1886: Upson, Grace (Photographs) 1881 (Box 1428, Folder 23)
- Class of 1886: Waite, Alice Vinton (Photographs, etc) 1931, other n.d. (Box 1428, Folder 24)
- Class of 1886: White, Harriet May (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1428, Folder 25)
- Class of 1886: Wilson, Jennie Blanche 1885 (Box 1428, Folder 26)
- Class of 1886: Wolcott, Charlotte Augusta (Box 1428, Folder 27)
- Class of 1886: Wright, Lucy Fitts (Box 1428, Folder 28)
- Class of 1886: Photograph Album 1886 (Box 1429)
- Class of 1886: Photograph Album 1886 (Box 1430)
- Class of 1886: Davis, Ellen Rich (Correspondence from Marie F. Kapp and Cecilie Kapp Precht) 1886-92 (Box 1431, Folder 1)
- Class of 1886: Davis, Ellen Rich (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1431, Folder 2)
- Class of 1886: Davis, Ellen Rich (Report to the class at their 45th reunion) 1931 (Box 1431, Folder 3)
- Class of 1886: Lecture Notes, Memorabilia Book Various dates (Box 1431)
- Class of 1886: Merriam, Florence Augusta 1889, 1912, 1921, 1952, 1971, 1987, 1990 (Box 1432, Folder 1)
- Class of 1886: Merriam, Florence Augusta (Class Letters of 1886) 1886-87, 1892-94, 1896-97, 1900-01, 1914-15, 1931-48, 1975 (Box 1432, Folder 2)
- Class of 1886: Merriam, Florence Augusta (Writings- Articles for Bird Lore) 1899, 1913, 1915-16, 1922 (Box 1432, Folder 3)
- Class of 1886: Merriam, Florence Augusta (Writings- Articles for The Audubon Magazine) 1887-88 (Box 1432, Folder 4)
- Class of 1886: Merriam, Florence Augusta (Writings- Articles for 'The Auk') 1890-1952 (Box 1432, Folder 5)
- Class of 1886: Merriam, Florence Augusta (Writings- Articles for Condor) 1906-1916 (Box 1432, Folder 6)
- Class of 1886: Merriam, Florence Augusta (Writings- Articles for Condor) 1916-1923 (Box 1432, Folder 7)
- Class of 1886: Merriam, Florence Augusta (Writings- Articles in The Oregon Statesman) 1916 (Box 1432, Folder 8)
- Class of 1886: Merriam, Florence Augusta (Writings- "Birds Recorded From the Santa Rita Mountains in Southern Arizona") 1923 (Box 1432, Folder 9)
- Class of 1886: Merriam, Florence Augusta (Writings- Articles for "General Information Regarding Glacier National Park") 1918-19 (Box 1432, Folder 10)
- Class of 1886: Merriam, Florence Augusta (Writings- "A Return to the Dakota Lake Region") 1918-20 (Box 1432, Folder 11)
- Class of 1886: Merriam, Florence Augusta (Writings- Misc. Writings) 1886-87, 1896, 1898, 1910-12, 1914, 1916-17, 1923-24, 1928 (Box 1432, Folder 12)
- Class of 1886: Slade, Abby M.B. (Student Notes) Various dates (Box 1433)
- Class of 1886: Stebbins, Mary Granger (Scrapbooks) Various dates (Box 1434)